It took 13 missions to get the only
color photographs of the surface [music]
of Venus. They were taken by this lander
that was only supposed to last 30
minutes, but somehow lasted 2 hours,
which is incredible because of Venus is
really not a good time. It's basically
hell. There are clouds of sulfuric acid,
surface pressure is 93 times that of
Earth, temperatures hot enough to melt
lead. The average moon lighter from that
time would be crushed in an instant. So,
Soviet engineers tinkered for 30 years
sending probes that failed over and over
again. [music] Starting with two flyby
missions. The first never made it out of
Earth's orbit. The second overheated
somewhere along the way. Mission three
crashed into the planet. Missions four,
five, six successfully sampled the
atmosphere, but then got crushed like
soda cans before reaching the ground.
Mission seven's parachute tore and then
it smashed into the planet, but it
managed to send [music] back the first
data from the surface showing us that
Venus, not a great vacation spot.
Mission eight didn't crash and confirmed
that data. And then they got even
craftier. So, they put all of the
electronics in an airtight insulated
container sealed with titanium, which is
one of the very few metals that wouldn't
get crushed or warped on the surface
immediately. [music] They even
pre-cooled the inside to give it a
little bit more time before overheating.
And they set up cameras behind windows
made of solid quartz, which is heat and
pressure resistant up to a point, but
still transparent enough to see through.
And it worked. Missions nine and 10 sent
back the first ever black and white
photographs of the surface. So, then
they did it again, but this time the
lens cap didn't pop off. So, they made
one final adjustment and sent two more
missions and we finally got the first
ever color photographs of Venus. And
sound. But now there's a plan to go back
to see it. Subscribe.